<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Careዘንጎ</title>
    <link>/</link>
      <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Careዘንጎ</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>@Careዘንጎ</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/%20</url>
      <title>Careዘንጎ</title>
      <link>/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Horrible attacks in Metekel,Benishangul gumuz Ethiopia!</title>
      <link>/2020/12/25/horrible-attacks-in-metekelbenishangul-gumuz-ethiopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2020/12/25/horrible-attacks-in-metekelbenishangul-gumuz-ethiopia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;የዜጎችን ደህንነት ማስጠበቅ ባልተቻለበት ሁኔታ ስለ ሠላም ማስከበር እና ልማት መደስኮር ወደ ብልጽግና አያሸጋግርም፡ ዛሬም ወገኖቻችን በህይወት የመኖር ተፈጥሮአዊ መብታቸው ሊከበርላቸው ባለመቻሉ ምንም በማይመለከታቸው ጉዳይ ምትክ የሌላት ህይወታቸውን እየገበሩ ነው፡፡ ሰሞኑ በቤኒሻንጉል ጉሙዝ ክልል መተከል ዞን በተካሄደው የንጹሀን ግድያ የተሰማንን ከፍተኛ ሀዘን እንገልፃለን፡ መንግስት ችግሮችን በቸልታ ከማለፍ ባሻገር ክልሉን በሚያስተዳድሩ ሃላፊዎች ላይ ምንም አይነት የማጣራትም ሆነ እርምጃ የመውሰድ ሁኔታ አይታይም፡ በዚህም ምክንያት ከጊዜ ወደ ጊዜ የሰላማዊ ዜጎች መፈናቀል እና ሞት በእጅጉ እየጨመረ መጥቷል፡፡ እኛ ኢትዮጵያዊያን ማንም እየተነሳ የሚያፈናቅለን ፣ የሚገድለን  እና ለስደት የሚዳርገን እስከመቼ እንደሆነ ባናውቅም ችግር ፈቺው መንግስታችን ግን “ሀገሪቱ ከጁንታ(TPLF) አገዛዝ ነጻ ወጥታለች ፣ ህዝቦቿም በብልጽግና ጎዳና ላይ ናቸው” እያለን ነው፡፡ &lt;strong&gt;እኛም እንላለን&lt;/strong&gt;:- ከብልጽግና እና መደመር በፊት የዜጎች በሀገራቸው በህይወት የመኖር መብት መከበር እንዲሁም በሰላም የመኖር ህልውና መረጋገጥ ይቀድማል፤ ህግና ስርዓት ሊከበር ይገባል ዝምታው ይብቃ፡፡&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One of the Ethiopian legendary singers,Hachalu Hundessa is murdered </title>
      <link>/2020/06/30/one-of-the-ethiopian-legendary-singershachalu-hundessa-is-murdered/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2020/06/30/one-of-the-ethiopian-legendary-singershachalu-hundessa-is-murdered/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unrest after Ethiopian singer Hachalu Hundessa&amp;rsquo;s killing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/u6pZfVJrXD0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ጉራጌ ክልል</title>
      <link>/talk/guraghe-region/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/guraghe-region/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/GurageKilil.jpg&#34;/&gt;    &lt;img src=&#34;/img/Gkilil.jpg&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/kilil.jpg&#34;/&gt;    &lt;img src=&#34;/img/Animated_flag.gif&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;አለም አቀፍ የጉራጌ ተወላጅ ማህበረሰብ ተወካዮች የጉራጌ ማህበረሰብ ራስን በራስ የማስተዳደር ህገመንግስታዊ ጥያቄና ለጠ/ሚ ስለተጻፈው ደብዳቤ ዝርዝር ሁኔታዎችን ለኢሳት አስረዱ&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7iRXp7oqZ_s&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker of Ethiopia&#39;s Upper House Resigns After Polls Postponed</title>
      <link>/2020/05/08/speaker-of-ethiopias-upper-house-resigns-after-polls-postponed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2020/05/08/speaker-of-ethiopias-upper-house-resigns-after-polls-postponed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ADDIS ABABA — Ethiopia&amp;rsquo;s upper house speaker resigned on Monday in apparent protest at the postponement of planned elections in the Horn of Africa country over the coronavirus, a sign of growing tension between her party and the government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The speaker Keria Ibrahim is also a top official in Tigray People&amp;rsquo;s Liberation Front (TPLF), one of the country&amp;rsquo;s major political parties and which has opposed the poll postponement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The parliamentary and regional elections had been planned for August ahead of the end of incumbent Prime Minister Abiy Ahmed&amp;rsquo;s term in September. No new date has yet been set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a televised speech, Keria accused Abiy&amp;rsquo;s government of taking away Ethiopians&amp;rsquo; sovereign rights, without elaborating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was widely understood to refer to the government&amp;rsquo;s decision to postpone the elections which effectively allowed Abiy to continue ruling beyond the expiry of his term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t be an accomplice when the constitution is being violated and a dictatorial government is being formed,&amp;rdquo; she said. &amp;ldquo;I have resigned not to be collaborator (with) such a historical mistake.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coronavirus</title>
      <link>/covid_19/covid_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/covid_19/covid_19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/Teaser-COVID-19.png&#34;/&gt;    &lt;img src=&#34;/img/Coronavirus-Schutzmaßnahmen-1-1.jpg&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ETHIOPIA 2019 HUMAN RIGHTS REPORT</title>
      <link>/publication/human_right_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/human_right_2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethiopia: Security forces &#39;must face justice for horrific human rights violations&#39; - New Report ==&gt;&gt; Amnesty International 29/05/20</title>
      <link>/publication/human_right_press_releases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/human_right_press_releases/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free speech restricted</title>
      <link>/2020/02/01/free-speech-restricted/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2020/02/01/free-speech-restricted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Ethiopian new law about banning social media.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;The Ethiopian government named it ‘a law banning online hate speech’. Is it really banning hate speech or banning social media? Does the hate speech in Ethiopia really started from social media? It is funny that the government knows some of the people and activists intensifying hate speech practically in the country and he is taking any action, but new law is implemented to ban social media. The following link directs to audio which is discussed about the issue by bbc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/w3csy67n&#34;&gt;https://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/w3csy67n&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;አሜሪካ ከአባይ ግድብ እጇን  እንድታነሳ የተቻለንን ሁሉ በማድረግ ሀገራዊ ግዴታችንን እንወጣ!!&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;/img/GrandEthiopianRenaissanceDamSaliniRendition.jpg&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;የኢትዮጵያ ህዝብ እየተራበ  በመቆጠብ ከፍተኛ ዋጋ የከፈለበትን ፕሮጀክት ዛሬላይ ዉጤቱን ለማየት በጉጉት በሚጠብቅበት ወቅት፡ የአሜሪካ መንግሰት አደራዳሪ ነኝ በሚል ሰበብ የሀገራችንን ጥቅም ለግብጽ ኣሳልፎ ለምስጠት የሚያደርገውን ጥረት ሊያቆም የገባል፡፡ በመሆኑም የትራምፕ መንግሰት የህዳሴን ግድብ በተመለከተ ምንም አይነት ድጋፍ ለግብጽ መንግስት ቢያደርግ የኢትዮጵያ ህዝብ በግልጽ እንደሚቃወመው ሁሉ የኢትዮጵያ መንግስትም የአሜሪካ መንግስትን ጣልቃገብነት በፍጹም አሻፈረኝ በማለት ሊኖሩበት የሚችሉ ጫናዎችን በመቋቋም ስራውን ማስቀጠል ይኖርበታል፡፡
ሐገራዊ ጥቅማችንን በጋራ እናስከብር!!&lt;/p&gt;
Careዘንጎ
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy and terms</title>
      <link>/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By using the website “www.carezengo.com”, you signify your agreement to these terms of use. If you do not agree to these terms of use, please do not use the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may download one copy of the materials on any single computer for your personal, non-commercial home use only, provided that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No modifications to the materials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are not allowed to use the materials in a manner that suggests an association with any of our products, services, or brands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You do not download quantities of materials to a database that can be used to avoid future downloads from this website. For the purposes of these terms, the use of any such material on any other website or computer environment is prohibited.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Careዘንጎ website contains copyrighted material and other proprietary information, including, but not limited to, text, photos, video, graphics, music, sound and software.
The entire contents of Careዘንጎ&amp;rsquo;s’ website is copyrighted under the  Academic theme for Hugo laws. You may not modify, publish, translate, transmit, participate in the transfer or sale, create derivative works, or in any way exploit, any of the content, in whole or in part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may download copyrighted material for your personal use only.
You shall not upload, post or otherwise make available on Careዘንጎ any material protected by copyright, trademark or other proprietary right without the express permission of the owner of the copyright, trademark or other proprietary right. You shall be solely liable for any damage resulting from any infringement of copyrights, proprietary rights, or any other harm resulting from such a submission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any unlawful use of the website can result in legal action.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
