<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Careዘንጎ</title>
    <link>/</link>
      <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Careዘንጎ</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Licensed to Careዘንጎ</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/Sengine</url>
      <title>Careዘንጎ</title>
      <link>/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy and terms</title>
      <link>/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By using the website “www.carezengo.com”, you signify your agreement to these terms of use. If you do not agree to these terms of use, please do not use the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may download one copy of the materials on any single computer for your personal, non-commercial home use only, provided that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No modifications to the materials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are not allowed to use the materials in a manner that suggests an association with any of our products, services, or brands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You do not download quantities of materials to a database that can be used to avoid future downloads from this website. For the purposes of these terms, the use of any such material on any other website or computer environment is prohibited.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Careዘንጎ website contains copyrighted material and other proprietary information, including, but not limited to, text, photos, video, graphics, music, sound and software.
The entire contents of Careዘንጎ&amp;rsquo;s’ website is copyrighted under the  Academic theme for Hugo laws. You may not modify, publish, translate, transmit, participate in the transfer or sale, create derivative works, or in any way exploit, any of the content, in whole or in part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may download copyrighted material for your personal use only.
You shall not upload, post or otherwise make available on Careዘንጎ any material protected by copyright, trademark or other proprietary right without the express permission of the owner of the copyright, trademark or other proprietary right. You shall be solely liable for any damage resulting from any infringement of copyrights, proprietary rights, or any other harm resulting from such a submission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any unlawful use of the website can result in legal action.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
