<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ኬርዘንጎ | Careዘንጎ</title>
    <link>/authors/%E1%8A%AC%E1%88%AD%E1%8B%98%E1%8A%95%E1%8C%8E/</link>
      <atom:link href="/authors/%E1%8A%AC%E1%88%AD%E1%8B%98%E1%8A%95%E1%8C%8E/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>ኬርዘንጎ</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>@Careዘንጎ</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/%20</url>
      <title>ኬርዘንጎ</title>
      <link>/authors/%E1%8A%AC%E1%88%AD%E1%8B%98%E1%8A%95%E1%8C%8E/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Horrible attacks in Metekel,Benishangul gumuz Ethiopia!</title>
      <link>/2020/12/25/horrible-attacks-in-metekelbenishangul-gumuz-ethiopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2020/12/25/horrible-attacks-in-metekelbenishangul-gumuz-ethiopia/</guid>
      <description> &lt;img src=&#34;/img/Met.jpg&#34;/&gt;
የዜጎችን ደህንነት ማስጠበቅ ባልተቻለበት ሁኔታ ስለ ሠላም ማስከበር እና ልማት መደስኮር ወደ ብልጽግና አያሸጋግርም፡ ዛሬም ወገኖቻችን በህይወት የመኖር ተፈጥሮአዊ መብታቸው ሊከበርላቸው ባለመቻሉ ምንም በማይመለከታቸው ጉዳይ ምትክ የሌላት ህይወታቸውን እየገበሩ ነው፡፡ ሰሞኑ በቤኒሻንጉል ጉሙዝ ክልል መተከል ዞን በተካሄደው የንጹሀን ግድያ የተሰማንን ከፍተኛ ሀዘን እንገልፃለን፡ መንግስት ችግሮችን በቸልታ ከማለፍ ባሻገር ክልሉን በሚያስተዳድሩ ሃላፊዎች ላይ ምንም አይነት የማጣራትም ሆነ እርምጃ የመውሰድ ሁኔታ አይታይም፡ በዚህም ምክንያት ከጊዜ ወደ ጊዜ የሰላማዊ ዜጎች መፈናቀል እና ሞት በእጅጉ እየጨመረ መጥቷል፡፡ እኛ ኢትዮጵያዊያን ማንም እየተነሳ የሚያፈናቅለን ፣ የሚገድለን  እና ለስደት የሚዳርገን እስከመቼ እንደሆነ ባናውቅም ችግር ፈቺው መንግስታችን ግን “ሀገሪቱ ከጁንታ(TPLF) አገዛዝ ነጻ ወጥታለች ፣ ህዝቦቿም በብልጽግና ጎዳና ላይ ናቸው” እያለን ነው፡፡ 
እኛም እንላለን:- ከብልጽግና እና መደመር በፊት የዜጎች በሀገራቸው በህይወት የመኖር መብት መከበር እንዲሁም በሰላም የመኖር ህልውና መረጋገጥ ይቀድማል፤ ህግና ስርዓት ሊከበር ይገባል ዝምታው ይብቃ፡፡
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethiopian journalist seeks asylum in UK</title>
      <link>/2020/01/24/ethiopian-journalist-seeks-asylum-in-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2020/01/24/ethiopian-journalist-seeks-asylum-in-uk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The current situation in Ethiopia is worse than before. The Nobel
peace prize Abiy Ahmed couldn’t make peace within the country, after he came to power
dozens of people were killed, large number of people are internally displaced because of their
identity. Experienced and influential journalists left the country and applied for asylum in
Australia and England due to harassment and prosecution they got from the government
officials for doing their jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bilal Worku, a senior journalist with Ethiopia’s state broadcaster(EBC) was on the team that accompanied deputy Prime Minister Demeke Mekonnen to the UK-Africa summit which took place in London. But He failed to return home as scheduled and subsequently sought asylum saying he had been threatened by high-ranking government officials&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
