<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1 | Careዘንጎ</title>
    <link>/publication_types/1/</link>
      <atom:link href="/publication_types/1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>1</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>@Careዘንጎ</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/%20</url>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>/publication_types/1/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker of Ethiopia&#39;s Upper House Resigns After Polls Postponed</title>
      <link>/2020/05/08/speaker-of-ethiopias-upper-house-resigns-after-polls-postponed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2020/05/08/speaker-of-ethiopias-upper-house-resigns-after-polls-postponed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ADDIS ABABA — Ethiopia&amp;rsquo;s upper house speaker resigned on Monday in apparent protest at the postponement of planned elections in the Horn of Africa country over the coronavirus, a sign of growing tension between her party and the government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The speaker Keria Ibrahim is also a top official in Tigray People&amp;rsquo;s Liberation Front (TPLF), one of the country&amp;rsquo;s major political parties and which has opposed the poll postponement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The parliamentary and regional elections had been planned for August ahead of the end of incumbent Prime Minister Abiy Ahmed&amp;rsquo;s term in September. No new date has yet been set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a televised speech, Keria accused Abiy&amp;rsquo;s government of taking away Ethiopians&amp;rsquo; sovereign rights, without elaborating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was widely understood to refer to the government&amp;rsquo;s decision to postpone the elections which effectively allowed Abiy to continue ruling beyond the expiry of his term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t be an accomplice when the constitution is being violated and a dictatorial government is being formed,&amp;rdquo; she said. &amp;ldquo;I have resigned not to be collaborator (with) such a historical mistake.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free speech restricted</title>
      <link>/2020/02/01/free-speech-restricted/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/2020/02/01/free-speech-restricted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Ethiopian new law about banning social media.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;The Ethiopian government named it ‘a law banning online hate speech’. Is it really banning hate speech or banning social media? Does the hate speech in Ethiopia really started from social media? It is funny that the government knows some of the people and activists intensifying hate speech practically in the country and he is taking any action, but new law is implemented to ban social media. The following link directs to audio which is discussed about the issue by bbc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/w3csy67n&#34;&gt;https://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/w3csy67n&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;አሜሪካ ከአባይ ግድብ እጇን  እንድታነሳ የተቻለንን ሁሉ በማድረግ ሀገራዊ ግዴታችንን እንወጣ!!&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;/img/GrandEthiopianRenaissanceDamSaliniRendition.jpg&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;የኢትዮጵያ ህዝብ እየተራበ  በመቆጠብ ከፍተኛ ዋጋ የከፈለበትን ፕሮጀክት ዛሬላይ ዉጤቱን ለማየት በጉጉት በሚጠብቅበት ወቅት፡ የአሜሪካ መንግሰት አደራዳሪ ነኝ በሚል ሰበብ የሀገራችንን ጥቅም ለግብጽ ኣሳልፎ ለምስጠት የሚያደርገውን ጥረት ሊያቆም የገባል፡፡ በመሆኑም የትራምፕ መንግሰት የህዳሴን ግድብ በተመለከተ ምንም አይነት ድጋፍ ለግብጽ መንግስት ቢያደርግ የኢትዮጵያ ህዝብ በግልጽ እንደሚቃወመው ሁሉ የኢትዮጵያ መንግስትም የአሜሪካ መንግስትን ጣልቃገብነት በፍጹም አሻፈረኝ በማለት ሊኖሩበት የሚችሉ ጫናዎችን በመቋቋም ስራውን ማስቀጠል ይኖርበታል፡፡
ሐገራዊ ጥቅማችንን በጋራ እናስከብር!!&lt;/p&gt;
Careዘንጎ
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
